Akhilesh Menghare

+91 7506599029 | akhil.menghare01@gmail.com

Profile Summary

- 3+ Years Professional experience in Information Technology with specialized skills on **SharePoint**, **SharePoint Online and Office 365 support**, **server administration and migration projects**.
- Worked on **SharePoint 2016 Hybrid** environment with SSO, Hybrid search and One Drive for business integration.
- Worked on Azure Resource manager portal on different tasks such as sync between Azure AD and with Windows AD with SSO, deploying VMs, Virtual Networks and subnetting, Creating VPN (Site- to site and Vnet to Vnet) etc
- Looking for challenges, where there is a scope for demonstration with a positive attitude, rigorous thinking and boundless curiosity and a learner for life with a fun attitude.

Technical Platform and Tools

Technology/Tools	Platform	Experience	Skill level
	WSS 3.0	2 Years	Intermediate
	MOSS 2007	2 Years	Intermediate
SharePoint	SharePoint 2010	3 Years	Expert
	SharePoint 2013	2 Years	Expert
	SharePoint 2016	18 Months	Proficient
Office 365	SharePoint Online	3 Years	Proficient
	Power BI	5 Months	Intermediate
	Resource Manager Portal	11 Months	Intermediate
Microsoft Azure	Azure Active Directory	5 Months	Intermediate
	Azure AD Sync	2 Years 18 Months 3 Years 5 Months 11 Months 5 Months 5 Months 3 Years	Intermediate
	2008R2, 2012R2	3 Years	Proficient
Window Server	Active Directory (ADFS, ADDS) 3 Years	Intermediate	
SQL Server	SQL Server 2012, 2014, 2016	3 Years	Intermediate

Windows PowerShell	Windows PowerShell	3 Years	Proficient
Sharegate	-	2 Years	Expert
Quest Migration Suite	-	6 Months	Proficient

Experience

Larson and Toubro Infotech (LTI)

July 2015 - Present

Systems Engineer

- Administration experience in SharePoint Online, SharePoint 2013, SharePoint 2010, MOSS 2007 and WSS 3.0
- Installation, Configuration and Migration experience from SharePoint 2010 to SharePoint 2013, SharePoint 2010, and SharePoint 2013 to SharePoint Online.
- Experienced in **Backup and Recovery** of Site Collections, Sites, & Items using PowerShell and DB backup respectively.
- Extensive experience in troubleshooting end user issues, Search Issues, UPA Issues and Content Server Issues
- Involved in planning, designing and POC of a **Hybrid SharePoint 2016 environment** involving Azure Site recovery spanning across the globe.

Work Summary

1. WLT SharePoint Online Migration

July,2018 - Present

The project involves identifying the existing gaps in the WLT SharePoint sites and providing a solution to migrate the content to SharePoint online as well as actual content migration

Responsibilities:

- Involved in planning and actual migration process.
- Analysed existing SharePoint 2013 environment.
- Created an analysis report by identifying the irregularities in the sites.
- Created Power shell scripts required to get the data for analysis.
- Documenting the SOPs and other deliverables

Tools: Sharegate and Nintex Workflows

Responsibilities:

- Handling L2 level of tickets related to SharePoint issues.
- Creating complex workflows using Nintex form and workflow as per business demands
- Maintaining Client SharePoint Servers.
- · Monitoring of Client environment.
- Handling Users SharePoint related queries.
- Good experience on Troubleshooting Permission related issues.
- Good knowledge in Solution Upgrade and Farm Deployment.
- Creating PowerShell scripts as per client requirement.

3. WSP SharePoint User Migration

Feb 2017 - Oct 2018

The project involves building the PowerShell scripts to perform various tasks involved in the process, such as, Pre-migration, Migration and permissions backup & cloning. The entire process is schedules in batches for script executions.

Responsibilities:

- Involved in planning of actual migration process.
- Documenting the SOPs and other deliverables
- Prepared PowerShell scripts as per the client requirements which are currently used for migration process.
- Created test environment consisting 3 domains and performed Active directory migration along with SharePoint user migration testing
- Providing support for any migration related queries

4. WSP SharePoint Admin Support

June 2016 - July,2018

Responsibilities:

- Handling L2 level of tickets related to SharePoint issues.
- Maintaining large no of Client SharePoint Servers.
- Monitoring of Client environment.
- Handling Users SharePoint related queries.
- Good experience on Troubleshooting Permission related issues.
- Good knowledge in Solution Upgrade and Farm Deployment.
- Creating PowerShell scripts as per client requirement.

The project involved providing a hybrid architecture, the hardware and software recommendations to build the infrastructure in different datacentres considering the data residency to support SharePoint 2016 application **Responsibilities:**

- Involved in planning process.
- Documenting the process documents and other deliverables
- Created a Hybrid SharePoint farm with Azure Site recovery along with Single Sign On for users as POC
- Studied the existing SharePoint infrastructure and worked on requirement
- Worked on Microsoft Visio to create technical diagrams
- Calculated the cost required to implement the proposed solution using tools such as Azure Pricing calculator

Tools: - Service Now, Office Online server, MIM, Azure Site recovery

6. WSP Remediation PAN Migration

Feb,2016 -July,2016

The project Involves Identifying Existing Gaps in the WSP environment across all the SharePoint farm and implementing remediation for them as well as migration of few PANs.

Responsibilities:

- Involved in planning and actual migration process.
- Analysed existing SharePoint 2007, 2010 and 2013 environment.
- Created an analysis report by identifying the irregularities in the farm.
- Created the gap closure report and remediation plan for each gap.
- Created Power shell scripts required while remediation of the farm.
- Documenting the SOPs and other deliverables
- Post Migration Customizations

Tools: Sharegate and Nintex Workflows

7. Marathon Oils SharePoint Migration

Jan 2016 - March 2016

The project involved the migration of SharePoint 2010 sites to SharePoint 2013 Environment using Quest migration tool for Marathon oil Company, USA.

Responsibilities:

- Worked as a Team Member.
- Content Migration and Customization of the 2013 environment.
- Documentation

Education Details

Degree / Course	Board / University / Institute	Year	Marks Obtained
BE (Electrical Engineering)	RGCER, Nagpur	2015	Aggregate- 73%
HSSC	Maharashtra Board	2011	76.12 %
SSC	Maharashtra Board	2009	89.53 %

Personal Details

Name : Akhilesh Chintaman Menghare

Address : Magdalena B-203, Casa Rio, Palava City, Kalyan-Shil Road - 421201

Date of Birth: 9th March 1994

Sex : Male

Marital Status : Single

Declaration and Signature

I hereby affirm that the information in this document is accurate and true to the b	est of my knowledge.
Place: Mumbai	
Date://	Akhilesh Menghare